

Profile

I am an experienced full stack developer who has a proven track record of producing quality code for production releases. I have published apps in the Google Play Store, the Apple App Store, the Overwolf store, and I have built production web apps from scratch. I also love to learn and I am capable of picking up new skills to fill any positional requirements.

Employment History

Lead Front End Developer at Liifer Technologies, Remote

May 2021 — November 2023

- In this position I wrote roughly 95% of the front end code that would end up in the production applications. I also made the decisions for front end stack, which includes React, Typescript, and Tailwind CSS.
- I selected and implemented the many modern libraries and tools included in the application. This includes but is not limited to: react-query, redux, react-router, axios, i18next, react-hook-form, react-table, google services API, Overwolf API, Ionic Capacitor, and react-testing-library.
- The back-end of the application is a REST API. This API has dozens
 of endpoints and is capable of everything you would expect from
 a modern food delivery application. The front end is connected to
 the endpoints using axios and custom React hooks created with
 react-query.
- This app proved efficient enough to used in an Overwolf extension, which allows gamers to order food while in-game, without slowing the performance of their PC. This app is currently available in the Overwolf store.
- I also ported this application to IOS and Android, through Ionic Capacitor. These ports passed verification and are available in the Apple App Store and the Google Play store.

Freelance Web Developer at SeonVision, Montréal

March 2021 — May 2021

- For this short-term contracted position, I built a landing page for a small start-up company for their application called SeonTaste. To do this I used tailwind CSS and React.
- I also did some work on their React Native application, which had been built by another contractor.

Details

Halifax, Nova Scotia Canada 5142334794 stephen.ricketts.dev@gmail.com

Links

stevedev.co liifer.com github.com/StephenRicketts

Skills

React

TypeScript

Tailwind CSS

Next.js

React Native

node.js

MongoDB

HTML & CSS

Git

Jira

Figma

Ionic Capacitor

Electron

Education

Diploma in Full-Stack Web Development, Concordia University, Montréal

September 2019 — December 2019

Completed 480+ hours of intensive full-stack web development course focused on programming fundamentals including test-driven development, object-oriented programming, SCRUM, Agile methodologies, pair-programming, algorithms and databases, with a focus on React and JavaScript.

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology, University of New Brunswick, Fredericton, New Brunswick

September 2008 — May 2012

Courses

React Native - The Practical Guide, Udemy

September 2020 — December 2020

React and TypeScript: Build a Portfolio Project (2021), Udemy

January 2021 — February 2021

◄ References

Patrick Ostiguy from Liifer patrick@liifer.com

David Ostiguy from Liifer david.ostiguy@liifer.com

Louis-Philippe Ostiguy from Liifer

louis-philippe@liifer.com